<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing about code, electronics and other stuff</title>
    <link>https://flicksfix.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Writing about code, electronics and other stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:07:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flicksfix.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Flannel Networking in K3s</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/understanding-flannel-networking-in-k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:07:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/understanding-flannel-networking-in-k3s/</guid>
      <description>How does it work without Flannel Assumption: I&amp;rsquo;m using host networking through these examples. You could utilize docker network for example, but to make it simple I wanted to stick to the fact below
container network = host/node network
If there was no Flannel, connection between containers would need to happen by directly connecting to the specific port that container is binding to
Like so:
#1 Node 10.0.0.10
 #1 Server Container binds onto port 5432 #2 Client Container connects to 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashing Android 7 onto Lenovo A3500-FL (Custom ROM, Recovery)</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/flashing-android-7-lenovo-a3500-fl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 15:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/flashing-android-7-lenovo-a3500-fl/</guid>
      <description>Long time ago I bought a tablet Lenovo A3500-FL. It&amp;rsquo;s really old tablet but still works suprisingly well. I thought about maybe having it working as a mobile terminal or Home Assistant Dashboard.
It only has offical upgrade to Android 4.4.2 which is really old and applications might not be targeting it anymore. According to XDA article only 4% of devices are still running Android that old (and 5,9% culminative of previous versions and this one).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K3s for Home Server the Easy Way pt. 1 - SSO, external access, traefik</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/k3s-for-home-server-the-easy-way-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 09:30:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/k3s-for-home-server-the-easy-way-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to have my own home server. I&amp;rsquo;ve even bought Intel NUC for that which I intended to use, but I never got around to configuring it properly so it has gathered dust while not in use.
But in motivation strike, I decided to finally get around to do it, and implement it.
Infra automation not always the best way to move forward First of all, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be it a maintanence burden at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in the IDE - or Why I Really Like HCL and Loathe YAML</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/living-in-the-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 17:07:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/living-in-the-ide/</guid>
      <description>There are things that I enjoy when working as a professional. One of them is that when the tooling is so good that it just makes want to write the code. Example of state-of-the-art integration of IDE into a language is what Hashicorp has done to the Terraform and its integration with IntelliJ IDEA.
An example of that you can find below
 Autocomplete works out of the box, no configuration needed   One might say &amp;ldquo;yeah, its just a simple gimmick, it will fall apart for more complex things!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infra as a Code Is Cloud Lock-In</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/infra-as-a-code-is-cloud-lock-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:23:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/infra-as-a-code-is-cloud-lock-in/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE (2021-08-06): In a hindsight I think I choose wrong title to describe the concept. More appropriate would be &amp;ldquo;Modern infra automation state management is gateway drug for using more cloud provided services&amp;rdquo; or something along these lines. Initial thought on title came from the fact that I considered terraform/pulumi to be truly &amp;ldquo;Infra as a code&amp;rdquo; solution, while Ansible (second tool that I use for automation) being subpar in that experience (and hence more of &amp;ldquo;commands over SSH&amp;rdquo; thing than true infra state manager).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Idea Where to Live</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/no-idea-where-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 13:38:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/no-idea-where-to-live/</guid>
      <description>Intro For unfamiliar with Polish economy For the context of this post - I currently live by renting a flat in Warsaw, almost by the city border (Far end of Ursynów district). See the attached view for having a context
 Here is how it looks like   I&amp;rsquo;ve pretty close connection to metro line (which to say is impressive here as Warsaw has only two metro lines).
Rent market !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tfui</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/tfui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/tfui/</guid>
      <description>Interactive terraform console UI for managing state (mainly renaming variables)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping ESP32 PWM LED Controller for Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/esp32-pwm-driver-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/esp32-pwm-driver-prototype/</guid>
      <description>After spending a couple of days laying in my bed with absolute no motivation at all to do anything I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do anything that will bring me from the lair of despair.
COVID situation here in Poland at the moment of writing the post is not really great, there is absolutely nothing to do outside because everything is cancelled.
I can either tinker in my &amp;ldquo;electronic workshop&amp;rdquo; or do programming which I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really keep motivation for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemrabot</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/gemrabot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/gemrabot/</guid>
      <description>Gitlab Merge Request Bot that allows interactive approval using slack (ChatOps)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threedverse</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/threedverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/threedverse/</guid>
      <description>My attempt to make alternative for hosting 3D printing content (*.stl)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hash Sum Mismatch – trouble when using WSL2 and VirtualBox</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/hash-sum-mismatch-virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/hash-sum-mismatch-virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>When I was writing a tutorial regarding usage of VirtualBox to compile Marlin firmware (for 3D Printers) I came across following issue:
E: Failed to fetch store:/var/lib/apt/lists/partial/jp.archive.ubuntu.com_ubuntu_dists_focal_main_binary-amd64_Packages.xz Hash Sum mismatch Hashes of expected file: - Filesize:5826751 [weak] - SHA256:af226b4496cbb524bd4814d102047ae77769836203274dffc91cb543d5da13cc - SHA1:aef5c36ce45bd5c3154a1bb03c62b6cfb33e2bc6 [weak] - MD5Sum:7ef83228ec207df10acac48fbdd81112 [weak] Hashes of received file: - SHA256:e2c7fc5a2d86f75f03612fec614dcf84d3d502976558fbe40928c1dd120bb05e - SHA1:aef5c36ce45bd5c3154a1bb03c62b6cfb33e2bc6 [weak] - MD5Sum:7ef83228ec207df10acac48fbdd81112 [weak] - Filesize:5826751 [weak] Last modification reported: Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:40:26 +0000 Release file created at: Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:33:17 +0000 This error was really strange because SHA256 is the only one that differs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paperless (fork)</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/paperless-fork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/paperless-fork/</guid>
      <description>My FORK of paperless which adds Azure OCR service for better OCR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker swarm cluster on single laptop home lab running Proxmox VE</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/docker-swarm-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/docker-swarm-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This is my first blog post about running anything related to home lab. As I have already done some work before to have Proxmox VE running with connection to the router — I will be explaining that in later posts if I find time or motivation to do so.
Planned:  I want to have 3 nodes of VM, with Ubuntu Server running on them, referring to them as Swarm Nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooter-Board-MCU</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/scooter-board-mcu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/scooter-board-mcu/</guid>
      <description>My attempt on reverse engineering Xiaomi M365 scooter UART communication</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>langenv (concept)</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/langenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 17:50:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/langenv/</guid>
      <description>Concept of making a universal language management tool</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arduino-fft-visualizer</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/arduino-visualizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 09:40:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/arduino-visualizer/</guid>
      <description>Ancient project for making LEDs flash according to given frequency played in my speaker using FFT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trellobot</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/projects/trellobot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 09:23:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/projects/trellobot/</guid>
      <description>My oldest public project, a bot which sends notifications about terllo events on slack</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
