<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Writing about code, electronics and other stuff</title>
    <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Writing about code, electronics and other stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 13:38:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flicksfix.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Idea Where to Live</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/no-idea-where-to-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 13:38:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/no-idea-where-to-live/</guid>
      <description>Intro For unfamiliar with Polish economy For the context of this post - I currently live by renting a flat in Warsaw, almost by the city border (Far end of Ursynów district). See the attached view for having a context
 Here is how it looks like   I&amp;rsquo;ve pretty close connection to metro line (which to say is impressive here as Warsaw has only two metro lines).
Rent market !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping ESP32 PWM LED Controller for Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/esp32-pwm-driver-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/esp32-pwm-driver-prototype/</guid>
      <description>After spending a couple of days laying in my bed with absolute no motivation at all to do anything I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do anything that will bring me from the lair of despair.
COVID situation here in Poland at the moment of writing the post is not really great, there is absolutely nothing to do outside because everything is cancelled.
I can either tinker in my &amp;ldquo;electronic workshop&amp;rdquo; or do programming which I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really keep motivation for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hash Sum Mismatch – trouble when using WSL2 and VirtualBox</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/hash-sum-mismatch-virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/hash-sum-mismatch-virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>When I was writing a tutorial regarding usage of VirtualBox to compile Marlin firmware (for 3D Printers) I came across following issue:
E: Failed to fetch store:/var/lib/apt/lists/partial/jp.archive.ubuntu.com_ubuntu_dists_focal_main_binary-amd64_Packages.xz Hash Sum mismatch Hashes of expected file: - Filesize:5826751 [weak] - SHA256:af226b4496cbb524bd4814d102047ae77769836203274dffc91cb543d5da13cc - SHA1:aef5c36ce45bd5c3154a1bb03c62b6cfb33e2bc6 [weak] - MD5Sum:7ef83228ec207df10acac48fbdd81112 [weak] Hashes of received file: - SHA256:e2c7fc5a2d86f75f03612fec614dcf84d3d502976558fbe40928c1dd120bb05e - SHA1:aef5c36ce45bd5c3154a1bb03c62b6cfb33e2bc6 [weak] - MD5Sum:7ef83228ec207df10acac48fbdd81112 [weak] - Filesize:5826751 [weak] Last modification reported: Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:40:26 +0000 Release file created at: Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:33:17 +0000 This error was really strange because SHA256 is the only one that differs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker swarm cluster on single laptop home lab running Proxmox VE</title>
      <link>https://flicksfix.com/posts/docker-swarm-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flicksfix.com/posts/docker-swarm-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This is my first blog post about running anything related to home lab. As I have already done some work before to have Proxmox VE running with connection to the router — I will be explaining that in later posts if I find time or motivation to do so.
Planned:  I want to have 3 nodes of VM, with Ubuntu Server running on them, referring to them as Swarm Nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
